The bastard of Winterfell.
The dwarf of Casterly Rock.
I believe we last saw each other atop the Wall.
You were pissing off the edge if I remember right.
Picked up some scars along the road.
It's been a long road, but we're both still here.
I'm Tyrion Lannister.
- Davos Seaworth. - Ah, the Onion Knight.
We fought on opposite sides at the Battle of Blackwater Bay.
Unluckily for me.
Missandei is the queen's most trusted advisor.
Welcome to Dragonstone.
Our queen knows it is a long journey.
She appreciates the efforts you have made on her behalf.
If you wouldn't mind handing over your weapons.
Of course.
Please, this way.
Where are you from?
I can't place the accent.
I was born on the Island of Naath.
I hear it's beautiful down there.
Palm trees and butterflies.
Haven't been, myself.
This place has changed.
And Sansa? I hear she's alive and well.
- She is. - Does she miss me terribly?
A sham marriage. And unconsummated.
- I didn't ask. - Well, it was. Wasn't.
Anyway...
she's much smarter than she lets on.
She's starting to let on.
Good.
At some point,
I want to hear how a Night's watch recruit became King in the North.
As long as you tell me how a Lannister
became Hand to Daenerys Targaryen.
A long and bloody tale.
To be honest, I was drunk for most of it.
My bannermen think I'm a fool for coming here.
Of course they do.
If I was your Hand, I would have advised against it.
General rule of thumb--
Stark men don't fare well when they travel south.
True...
but I'm not a Stark.
I'd say you get used to them...
but you never really do.
Come, their mother is waiting for you.
I wondered why you weren't there to meet our guests.
You begged us to summon the King in the North.
Don't you want to see him again?
I've done my part.
I've brought ice and fire together.
Strange.
You spoke so highly of Jon Snow,
but when he arrives, you hide on a cliff.
I didn't take you for a bashful girl.
My time whispering in the ears of kings has come to an end.
Oh, I doubt that.
Give us common folk one taste of power,
we're like the lion who tasted man.
Nothing is ever so sweet again.
Neither of us is common folk anymore.
I did not part on good terms
with the King in the North or his advisor.
Why?
Because of mistakes I made.
Terrible mistakes.
I would only be a distraction if I stayed.
- So, where will you go? - Volantis.
Good.
If you don't mind my saying,
I don't think you should return to Westeros.
I'm not sure you'd be safe here.
Oh, I will return, dear Spider.
- One last time. - My lady--
I have to die in this strange country.
Just like you.
You stand in the presence
of Daenerys Stormborn of House Targaryen,
rightful heir to the Iron Throne,
rightful Queen of the Andals and the First Men,
Protector of the Seven Kingdoms,
the Mother of Dragons,
the Khaleesi of the Great Grass Sea,
the Unburnt, the Breaker of Chains.
This is Jon Snow.
He's King in the North.
Thank you for traveling so far, my lord.
I hope the seas weren't too rough.
The winds were kind, Your Grace.
Apologies, I have a Flea Bottom accent, I know,
but Jon Snow is King in the North, Your Grace.
- He's not a lord. - Forgive me--
Your Grace, this is Ser Davos Seaworth.
Forgive me, Ser Davos.
I never did receive a formal education,
but I could have sworn I read
the last King in the North was Torrhen Stark,
who bent the knee to my ancestor, Aegon Targaryen.
In exchange for his life and the lives of the Northmen,
Torrhen Stark swore fealty to House Targaryen in perpetuity.
Or do I have my facts wrong?
I wasn't there, Your Grace.
No, of course not.
But still, an oath is an oath.
And perpetuity means--
what does perpetuity mean, Lord Tyrion?
Forever.
So I assume, my lord...
...you're here to bend the knee.
I am not.
Well, that is unfortunate.
You've traveled all this way
to break faith with House Targaryen?
Break faith?
Your father burned my grandfather alive.
He burned my uncle alive.
He would have burned the Seven Kingdoms--
My father... was an evil man.
On behalf of House Targaryen...
I ask your forgiveness
for the crimes he committed against your family.
And I ask you not to judge a daughter
by the sins of her father.
Our two houses were allies for centuries,
and those were the best centuries
the Seven Kingdoms have ever known.
Centuries of peace and prosperity
with a Targaryen sitting on the Iron Throne
and a Stark serving as Warden of the North.
I am the last Targaryen, Jon Snow.
Honor the pledge your ancestor made to mine.
Bend the knee and I will name you Warden of the North.
Together, we will save this country from those who would destroy it.
You're right.
You're not guilty of your father's crimes.
And I'm not beholden to my ancestor's vows.
Then why are you here?
Because I need your help, and you need mine.
Did you see three dragons flying overhead when you arrived?
I did.
And did you see the Dothraki,
all of whom have sworn to kill for me?
They're hard to miss.
But still, I need your help?
Not to defeat Cersei.
You could storm King's Landing tomorrow and the city would fall.
Hell, we almost took it
and we didn't even have dragons.
- Almost. - But you haven't stormed King's Landing.
Why not?
The only reason I can see
is you don't want to kill thousands of innocent people.
It's the fastest way to win the war,
but you won't do it,
which means, at the very least,
you're better than Cersei.
Still, that doesn't explain why I need your help.
Because right now, you and I and Cersei and everyone else,
we're children playing at a game,
screaming that the rules aren't fair.
- You told me you liked this man. - I do.
In the time since he's met me, he's refused to call me queen,
he's refused to bow, and now he's calling me a child.
I believe he's calling all of us children. Figure of speech.
Your Grace, everyone you know will die before winter's over
if we don't defeat the enemy to the north.
As far as I can see, you are the enemy to the north.
I am not your enemy.
The dead are the enemy.
The dead?
Is that another figure of speech?
The Army of the Dead is on the march.
The Army of the Dead?
You don't know me well, my lord,
but do you think I'm a liar or a madman?
No, I don't think you're either of those things.
The Army of the Dead is real.
The white walkers are real.
The Night King is real. I've seen them.
If they get past the Wall
and we're squabbling amongst ourselves...
we're finished.
I was born at Dragonstone.
Not that I can remember it.
We fled before Robert's assassins could find us.
Robert was your father's best friend, no?
I wonder if your father knew his best friend sent assassins
to murder a baby girl in her crib.
Not that it matters now, of course.
I spent my life in foreign lands.
So many men have tried to kill me,
I don't remember all their names.
I have been sold like a broodmare.
I've been chained and betrayed,
raped and defiled.
Do you know what kept me standing
through all those years in exile?
Faith.
Not in any gods,
not in myths and legends.
In myself.
In Daenerys Targaryen.
The world hadn't seen a dragon in centuries
until my children were born.
The Dothraki hadn't crossed the sea, any sea.
They did for me.
I was born to rule the Seven Kingdoms,
and I will.
You'll be ruling over a graveyard
if we don't defeat the Night King.
The war against my sister has already begun.
You can't expect us to halt hostilities and join you in fighting
whatever you saw beyond the Wall.
You don't believe him.
I understand that. It sounds like nonsense.
But if destiny has brought
Daenerys Targaryen back to our shores,
it has also made Jon Snow King in the North.
You were the first to bring Dothraki to Westeros?
He is the first to make allies of wildlings and Northmen.
He was named Lord Commander of the Night's Watch.
He was named King in the North.
Not because of his birthright.
He has no birthright. He's a damn bastard.
All those hard sons of bitches chose him as their leader
because they believe in him.
All those things you don't believe in,
he faced those things.
He fought those things for the good of his people.
He risked his life for his people.
He took a knife in the heart for his people.
He gave his own--
If we don't put aside our enmities and band together,
we will die.
And then it doesn't matter whose skeleton sits on the Iron Throne.
If it doesn't matter, then you might as well kneel.
Swear your allegiance to Queen Daenerys,
help her to defeat my sister,
and together, our armies will protect the North.
There's no time for that.
There's no time for any of this!
While we stand here, debating--
It takes no time to bend the knee.
Pledge your sword to her cause.
And why would I do that?
I mean no offense, Your Grace,
but I don't know you.
As far as I can tell,
your claim to the throne rests entirely on your father's name,
and my own father fought to overthrow the Mad King.
The lords of the North
placed their trust in me to lead them,
and I will continue to do so as well as I can.
That's fair.
It's also fair to point out
that I'm the rightful Queen of the Seven Kingdoms.
By declaring yourself king of the northernmost kingdom,
you are in open rebellion.
Your Grace, please dismiss your guests.
I have grave news.
You must forgive my manners.
You'll both be tired after your long journey.
We'll have baths drawn for you and supper sent to your rooms.
Am I your prisoner?
Not yet.
Our ironborn and Dornish allies were attacked en route to Dorne.
- And? - Two or three ships escaped,
the rest, sunk or captured.
Ellaria and the Sand Snakes, dead or captured.
The Greyjoys, dead or captured.
All of them?
- Pull! - Heave!
Pull!
Your sister's dead?
Euron has her.
You saw him take her?
- But you got away? - I couldn't save her.
I tried.
You wouldn't be here if you tried.
Come, men!
Sails up!
Murderer!
Whores!
Traitor!
This is the life.
Look at them, cheering for a Greyjoy.
I have to be honest,
this is making me hard.
Did you see Little Theon's face right before he jumped overboard?
"Oh, no!"
What a twat.
- Whore! Whore! Whore! - Murderers!
My queen, please accept this gift
on behalf of all of your loyal subjects in the Iron Islands.
I give you what no other man could give--
justice.
Justice for your murdered daughter.
You've proven yourself the greatest captain on the fourteen seas
and a true friend to the crown.
You deserve more than a true friend.
And you deserve a proper reward for your heroism.
There's only one reward I want.
You shall have what your heart desires...
when the war is won.
With Euron Greyjoy commanding our naval forces
and Jaime Lannister leading our armies,
the sons and daughters of Westeros
shall defend our country.
There's nothing quite like it, is there?
The love of the people.
Though I suppose you wouldn't know.
This same mob spat at my sister not long ago.
And if you turn on us,
they'll cheer to see your head mounted on a spike.
Or yours.
They just like severed heads, really.
Listen, if you have any advice at all,
I would love to hear it.
When we have an hour or two to speak as brothers.
Advice?
Does she like it gentle or rough?
A finger in the bum?
Not now. We'll talk later.
I want you to know I understand.
Even though we're enemies, you and I,
I understand the fury that drives you.
I was there that day when Ser Gregor
crushed your lover's head.
If I close my eyes,
I can hear the sound of Oberyn's skull breaking.
The sound of your scream.
I never heard a sound like that.
I thought, "That's true love."
Oberyn looked beautiful that day. He really did.
No one moved like him.
No one had such skill with a spear.
Even Ser Gregor couldn't stop him.
If only he hadn't taunted him.
He could've walked away and left poor Ser Gregor to die.
But that wasn't your lover's way, was it?
Now he's buried somewhere.
And here's Ser Gregor, stronger than ever.
That must be difficult for you.
When my daughter was taken from me,
my only daughter...
well, you can't imagine how that feels
unless you've lost a child.
I fed her at my own breast even though they told me
to give her to the wet nurse.
I couldn't bear to see her in another woman's arms.
I never got to have a mother,
but Myrcella did.
She was mine, and you took her from me.
Why did you do that?
Doesn't matter now.
Your daughter's a beauty, too.
Those brown eyes.
Those lips.
Perfect Dornish beauty.
I imagine she's your favorite.
I know, I know, we're not supposed to have favorites,
but still, we're only human.
We love whom we love.
I'm sorry, I can't understand you.
That gag makes it impossible to understand what you're saying.
It must be frustrating.
We all make our choices.
You chose to murder my daughter.
You must have felt powerful after you made that choice.
Do you feel powerful now?
I don't sleep very well.
Not at all, really.
I lie in bed and I stare at the canopy
and imagine ways of killing my enemies.
How to destroy Ellaria Sand,
the woman who murdered my only daughter.
I thought about having Ser Gregor crush your skull
the way he did Oberyn's.
It would be poetic, I suppose, but fast, too fast.
I thought about having him crush your daughter's skull.
She's so beautiful.
The thought of this lovely face
cracking open like a duck egg,
no, it's just not right.
Mama.
Qyburn here is the cleverest man I know.
Clever enough to learn what poison you used to murder Myrcella.
The Long Goodbye, was that it?
- The Long Farewell. - That's the one.
How long does the poison take?
Difficult to say-- hours, days.
It depends on the subject's constitution.
But death is certain?
Oh, yes, Your Grace, quite certain.
Your daughter will die here in this cell,
and you will be here watching when she does.
You'll be here the rest of your days.
If you refuse to eat, we'll force food down your throat.
You will live to watch your daughter rot.
To watch that beautiful face collapse...
...to bone and dust.
All the while contemplating the choices you've made.
Make sure the guards change the torches every few hours.
I don't want her to miss a thing.
No.
Don't.
What are you doing? No one can see us like this.
I am the Queen of the Seven Kingdoms. I'll do as I please.
Forgive me, Your Grace.
The visitor from Braavos has arrived.
Good. And we'll need fresh sheets for the bed.
At once, Your Grace.
No, thank you.
My condolences, Your Grace,
on the death of your son.
From all reports, he was a fine young man.
The Iron Bank didn't send you here to offer condolences.
Condolences and congratulations.
To become the first ruling Queen of the Seven Kingdoms,
that's quite an accomplishment.
The Iron Bank appreciates
how you cast off the yoke of superstition,
freeing the crown from elements
who sought to subvert the rule of law.
The destruction of the Sept of Baelor was a tragic accident.
Indeed, but sometimes tragedies are necessary
to restore order and rational leadership.
The Iron Bank wants its gold back.
Your father never minced words either.
But, yes, your debts are considerable.
And you're now engaged in a conflict on several fronts.
We both know how expensive war can be.
And we both know gold wins wars.
Your vaults are empty.
Your late husband's profligacy saw to that.
Your wealthiest allies, the Tyrells, are now your enemies.
You are surrounded on all sides by rivals for the throne.
And the Iron Bank wants to bet on a winner.
We don't make bets.
We invest in endeavors we deem likely to be successful.
A fancy way of saying "Bet."
The war's already begun. I've drawn first blood.
I decapitated the Dornish snake.
My armada owns the Narrow Sea.
Euron Greyjoy's armada owns the Narrow Sea.
Euron Greyjoy is loyal to me.
For now.
Daenerys Targaryen has three full-grown dragons.
How well do wooden ships fare against fire-breathing dragons?
Her dragons might not be as invulnerable as some think.
But let's talk about the Targaryen girl.
You want to invest in her?
I'm guessing the Iron Bank
invested considerable gold in the slave trade.
How are your profits
now that Daenerys has freed all the slaves?
The slave trade has entered a downturn, it's true.
From what I gather, she considers herself
more of a revolutionary than a monarch.
In your experience,
how do bankers usually fare with revolutionaries?
The Lannisters owe the Iron Bank quite a lot of money,
but Lannisters always pay their debts.
Do former slaves or Dothraki or dragons?
Your father's daughter, indeed.
Give me a fortnight.
Stay in King's Landing as my honored guest.
And when you return to Braavos,
I swear to you, my debt will be paid in full.
I came down here to brood over my failure
to predict the Greyjoy attack.
You're making it difficult.
You look a lot better brooding than I do.
You make me feel like I'm failing at brooding over failing.
I'm a prisoner on this island.
I wouldn't say you're a prisoner on this island.
You're free to walk the castle,
the beaches, to go wherever you want.
Except to my ship.
You took my ship.
I wouldn't say we took your ship.
I'm not playing word games with you.
The dead are coming for us all.
Why don't you figure out what to do
about my missing fleet and murdered allies,
and I'll figure out what to do about your walking dead men.
It's hard for me to fathom. It really is.
If someone told me about the white walkers and the Night King...
You probably don't believe me.
I do, actually.
You didn't before.
"Grumkins and snarks," You called them.
Do you remember?
You said it was all nonsense.
It was nonsense. Everybody knew it.
But then Mormont saw them
and you saw them.
And I trust the eyes of an honest man
more than I trust what everybody knows.
How do I convince people who don't know me
that an enemy they don't believe in is coming to kill them all?
- Good question. - I know it's a good question.
I'm looking for an answer.
People's minds aren't made for problems that large.
White walkers, the Night King,
Army of the Dead--
it's almost a relief to confront
a comfortable, familiar monster like my sister.
I need to help prepare my people for what's coming.
I can't help them from here.
I'd like to leave.
It seems unlikely that you became King in the North
by giving up that easily.
Everyone told me to learn from my father's mistakes.
Don't go south.
Don't answer a summons from the Mad King's daughter,
a foreign invader.
And here I am,
a Northern fool.
Children are not their fathers,
luckily for all of us.
And sometimes there's more to foreign invaders
and Northern fools than meets the eye.
Daenerys could have sailed for Westeros long ago,
but she didn't.
Instead, she stayed where she was
and saved many people from horrible fates,
some of whom are on this island with us right now.
While you're our guest here,
you might consider asking them
what they think of the Mad King's daughter.
She protects people from monsters,
just as you do.
It's why she came here.
And she's not about to head north
to fight an enemy she's never seen
on the word of a man she doesn't know.
After a single meeting,
it's not a reasonable thing to ask.
So, do you have anything reasonable to ask?
What do you mean?
Maybe you are a Northern fool.
I'm asking if there's something I can do to help you.
- Dragonglass? - Yes.
Volcanic glass, obsidian.
He says you have a tremendous amount of it here.
Why are we talking about glass?
We just lost two of our allies.
Which is why I was speaking to Jon Snow, a potential ally.
And what does the King in the North want with dragonglass?
Apparently, it can be turned into weapons
that kill white walkers and their foot soldiers.
Or stop them.
Destroy them.
Unsure about the nomenclature.
And what do you think about this Army of the Dead
and white walkers and Night Kings?
I'd very much like to believe that Jon Snow is wrong.
But a wise man once said that you should never believe a thing
simply because you want to believe it.
Which wise man said this?
I don't remember.
Are you trying to present your own statements as ancient wisdom?
I would never do that.
To you.
The reason I believe Jon Snow is because he's here.
All of his advisors would have told him not to come.
I would have told him not to come.
And he's here anyway.
You don't have to believe him.
Let him mine the dragonglass.
If he's wrong, it's worthless.
You didn't even know it was here.
It's nothing to you.
Give him something by giving him nothing.
Take a step toward a more productive relationship
with a possible ally.
Keep him occupied while we focus on the task at hand
Casterly Rock.
What was that Ser Davos said
about taking a knife in the heart for his people?
Did you notice that?
You must allow them their flights of fancy.
It's dreary in the North.
Amazing thing to see.
I named them for my brothers, Viserys and Rhaegar.
They're both gone now.
You lost two brothers as well.
People thought dragons were gone forever, but here they are.
Perhaps we should all be examining what we think we know.
You've been talking to Tyrion.
He is my Hand.
- He enjoys talking. - We all enjoy what we're good at.
I don't.
You know I'm not going to let Cersei stay on the Iron Throne.
I never expected that you would.
And I haven't changed my mind
about which kingdoms belong to that throne.
I haven't either.
I will allow you to mine
the dragonglass and forge weapons from it.
Any resources or men you need, I will provide for you.
Thank you.
So you believe me, then,
about the Night King and the Army of the Dead?
You'd better get to work, Jon Snow.
How much do we have?
4,000 bushels, my lady.
What does that mean?
For the current occupants of the castle,
it's enough food for a year, perhaps more.
And what's the longest winter in the past hundred years?
Uh, I'm not entirely certain.
I'll check Maester Luwin's records.
He kept a copy of every raven scroll.
You're telling me we don't have enough food,
especially not if the armies
of the North come back to defend Winterfell?
No, my lady, most likely not.
Then we must prepare for that eventuality.
Whatever direction the threat comes from,
this is the best place to be.
We need to start building up our grain stores
with regular shipments from every keep in the North.
If we don't use it by winter's end, we'll give it back to them.
But if the entire North has to flee to Winterfell,
they won't have enough time to bring
wagonloads of grain with them.
Very wise, my lady.
Maester Wolkan, you'll see to it?
Are they covering those breastplates in leather?
No, my lady.
Well, shouldn't they be? Once the real cold comes?
They should, indeed.
Pardon me, my lady.
You there, why isn't there leather on these?
Command suits you.
The Northerners are all facing north,
worried about the threat from beyond the Wall.
So they should be.
I know Cersei better than anyone here.
You don't know Cersei better than anyone here.
That the woman who murdered my mother,
father, and brother is dangerous?
Thank you for your wise counsel.
One of two things will happen,
either the dead will defeat the living,
in which case...
all our troubles come to an end,
or life will win out.
And what then?
Don't fight in the North or the South.
Fight every battle, everywhere, always, in your mind.
Everyone is your enemy,
everyone is your friend,
every possible series of events is happening all at once.
Live that way and nothing will surprise you.
Everything that happens will be something
that you've seen before.
Lady Sansa, at the gate.
Hello, Sansa.
I wish Jon were here.
Yes, I need to speak to him.
You're Father's last living trueborn son.
You're Lord of Winterfell now.
I can never be Lord of Winterfell.
I can never be lord of anything.
I'm the Three-Eyed Raven.
I don't know what that means.
It's difficult to explain.
Try. Please, for me.
It means I can see everything.
Everything that's ever happened to everyone.
Everything that's happening right now.
It's all pieces now, fragments.
I need to learn to see better.
When the Long Night comes again,
I need to be ready.
How do you know all this?
The Three-Eyed Raven taught me.
I thought you were the Three-Eyed Raven.
I told you it's difficult to explain.
Bran--
I'm sorry for all that's happened to you.
I'm sorry it had to happen here in our home.
It was so beautiful that night.
Snow falling, just like now.
And you were so beautiful...
in your white wedding dress.
I have to go back inside, Bran.
I'll stay a bit longer.
Does it hurt?
A bit. Less than before.
The infection no longer appears to be active.
Unusual.
Unlikely.
One could almost be forgiven for thinking that the entire
upper layer of diseased skin was debrided
and the underlying region treated with some sort of unguent.
Don't know anything about that.
I just started feeling better.
I assumed it was the rest that did it.
And the climate.
The climate.
You're free to go, ser.
This chamber is needed for the infectious,
which you are no longer.
Tarly, I'd like to speak with you in my study this evening.
How bad is it?
Suppose I'll find out this evening.
Where will you go?
I surrendered to this sickness the moment I first saw it.
I knew it would kill me
or I'd kill myself before it could.
Daenerys Stormborn convinced me otherwise.
The only place for me is back with her.
I owe her my life.
Her and you.
Your father saved me more than once.
It's the least I could do.
Perhaps our paths will cross again.
I hope they do.
- You treated him? - Yes.
Who told you to treat him?
No one.
Who forbade you, or anyone, to attempt to treat him?
I seem to remember you.
- But you treated him anyway? - I did, yes.
I forbade it because it is dangerous and rarely successful,
especially on someone of that age.
You could have infected yourself and others.
You could have devastated the entire Citadel.
But you didn't.
It's a meticulous, difficult procedure.
Many maesters whose chains are heavy with healing links
have attempted it and failed.
Yet you succeeded.
How?
I read the books and followed the instructions.
That man is alive because of you.
You should be proud.
Thank you, Archmaester.
Come here.
All these manuscripts and scrolls are rotting away.
I need you to make copies of them.
You were expecting a reward.
Your reward is not being immediately expelled from the Citadel.
You'd better get started.
And careful of the paper mites.
They like flesh as well.
We need to find Euron Greyjoy's fleet and sink it.
Your Grace, he's already destroyed a good portion of our fleet.
To send our remaining ships after him--
I'm not talking about sending our ships after him.
Would you have to go yourself?
Euron's ships could be anywhere
or in more than one place.
You'd be flying around the open seas alone
for who knows how long.
I wouldn't be alone.
I would have Drogon, Viserion, and Rhaegal.
What can anyone do to them?
They can still do something to you.
It only takes one arrow.
It's too great a risk. You're too important.
What about Casterly Rock?
The Unsullied will be there soon.
And what will they face?
A difficult situation.
They know we're coming.
Yes. Cersei believes my sole purpose in life
is to destroy House Lannister.
She will be ready.
- No one has ever taken the Rock. - Archers!
The Lannister Army is still the army my father built.
- Come on! - Well-trained and well-provisioned.
10,000 men at least.
They will see us coming.
They will be ready.
Draw! Loose! Loose!
The gates of Casterly Rock are impregnable.
The fight up the walls will be hard.
We will be at a disadvantage.
Many men will die.
Just as my father said they would.
Interesting thing about my father--
he built our house up from near ruin.
He built our army, he built Casterly Rock as we know it,
but he didn't build the sewers.
That was beneath him,
so he gave the job to the lowest person he could find--
me.
He was right, I was low.
The company I kept, low.
Women, mostly.
They weren't welcome at the Rock.
Father disapproved of that sort of behavior.
Couldn't walk them through the front gates,
I couldn't have them in my chambers,
so in the process of building the sewers,
I threw in something for myself.
It was a passage that began
in an out of the way cove by the sea
and ended beneath one of the main guard towers.
No better place for low pursuits than beneath the ground.
Casterly Rock is an impregnable fortress.
But as a good friend of mine once said,
"Give me 10 good men and I'll impregnate the bitch."
And so it begins.
They will face the bulk of the Lannister forces.
They will be outnumbered.
They will have less armor and fewer weapons.
But my sister's armies fight for her out of fear.
The Unsullied will be fighting for something greater.
They will be fighting for freedom
and the person who gave it to them.
They will be fighting for you.
And that is why they will triumph.
Where are they?!
Where are the rest of the Lannisters?
- It's done. - It is.
And now the rains weep o'er our halls.
Did we fight well?
Uh, as well as could be expected.
It was never our forte.
Golden roses, indeed.
Your brother and his new queen
thought you would be defending Casterly Rock.
The truth is Casterly Rock isn't worth much anymore.
Well, it is to me,
but my fond childhood memories
won't keep Cersei on the throne.
So you just let them take it?
For now. They won't be able to hold it.
Euron Greyjoy's navy burned their ships,
we emptied the larders before we left.
Eventually, they'll be forced to abandon their position
and march all the way across Westeros.
And you took your army, your real army,
and went where they weren't.
As Robb Stark did to me at Whispering Wood.
There are always lessons in failures.
Yes. You must be very wise by now.
My father always said I was a slow learner.
If he was so clever,
why didn't he take Highgarden
the moment your gold mines ran dry?
I suppose I'll be able to ask him myself soon enough.
No more learning from my mistakes, eh?
How will you do it?
With that sword?
That was Joffrey's sword, wasn't it?
Not that he ever used it.
What did he call it?
Widow's Wail.
He really was a cunt, wasn't he?
I did unspeakable things to protect my family.
Or watched them being done on my orders.
I never lost a night's sleep over them.
They were necessary.
And whatever I imagined necessary
for the safety of House Tyrell, I did.
But your sister has done things...
I was incapable of imagining.
That was my prize mistake--
a failure of imagination.
She's a monster, you do know that?
To you, I'm sure.
To others as well.
But after we've won and there's no one left to oppose us,
when people are living peacefully in the world she built,
do you really think they'll
wring their hands over the way she built it?
You love her.
You really do love her.
You poor fool.
She'll be the end of you.
Possibly.
Not much to be gained
from discussing it with you, though, is there?
What better person to discuss it with?
What better guarantee could you have
that the things you say will never leave this room?
But perhaps you're right.
If she's driven you this far,
it's gone beyond your control.
Yes.
It has.
She's a disease.
I regret my role in spreading it.
You will, too.
I think we're done here.
How will it happen?
Cersei had several ideas.
Whipping you through the streets
and beheading you in front of the Red Keep.
Flaying you alive and
hanging you from the walls of King's Landing.
I talked her out of those.
Will there be pain?
No. I made sure of that.
That's good.
I'd hate to die like your son.
Clawing at my neck,
foam and bile spilling from my mouth,
eyes bloodred, skin purple.
Must have been horrible for you,
as a Kingsguard, as a father.
It was horrible enough for me.
A shocking scene.
Not at all what I intended.
You see, I had never seen the poison work before.
Tell Cersei.
I want her to know it was me.
My only venture at this moment
is reestablishing control over this continent
and every person on it.